ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
潇湘月影
翻译
煮粥达人
某羽
翻译
showeryhe
滚成一个团子
翻译
木浅薰
某茶晚安
翻译
冬麟
时间轴
Kallen   今   兜兜兜爹
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第二季
第二集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
这是在保加利亚高山滑雪
Heli-skiing in Bulgaria.
我住的小屋里的床跟苏联监狱的床一样破
The chalet I stayed at had beds like a Soviet prison.
但是那雪
But the snow--
棒极了
oh, my God.
你的第一份工作就在石油业吗
Was your first job in oil?
当然不是
Hell, no.
我父母开了间小店卖地毯
My parents ran a carpet store.
直到二十多一直在那儿帮忙
Worked there into my 20s.
石油在我那时看来只是种脏东西
Oil was just a stain to me.
更何况他的主要企图
Well, not to mention that his main ambition
是下班后带姑娘过去
was bringing girls there after hours.
我哥哥竟然跟你讲这个
Remind me to kill my brother
记得提醒我干掉他
for ever telling you that story.
后来怎么改主意了
What derailed those big plans?
男人总有一日
Well, there comes a time
要独立打拼的
when a man's gotta strike out on his own.
商店烧毁了
Store burned down.
好吧  这也算原因之一
Okay, that, too.
我当时26岁  一无所长
So, at 26, unskilled,
进入社会开始打拼
I set out to eat the world for breakfast.
我找到的唯一一份工作
The only job I could find
就是处理
was managing the sludge
克利夫兰市郊一家橡胶厂的废料
from a rubber plant just outside of Cleveland.
我老板让我偷工减料
My boss had me cut some corners
结果把河烧着了
and the river caught fire.
凯霍加河
Cuyahoga River?
不用说  我被炒了鱿鱼
'Course I got fired anyway,
尽管我只是听老板吩咐做事
even though I just worked for the guy
而老板也是听上头的吩咐做事
who was working for the guy.
我要说的是
The point being--
自己做老板永远比替人做事好
It's always better to be the guy.
我总爱这么说  亲爱的
That's my usual joke, sweetheart,
但是为了不老调重弹
but just to show I can surprise you,
我要说的是  我们都得经历艰辛
the point being we all have to take our lumps
才能挣到大钱
before we come into our own.
这样的成功才更甜美
Makes getting there all the more sweet.
那么  你爱上我女儿了
So, you're in love with my daughter, huh?
爸
Dad.
怎么  你不想听答案吗
What, you don't want to know the answer?
他无可救药了
Okay, he's impossible.
别理他
Just ignore him.
有其父必有其女
And she's an apple from the tree.
好吧  我去跟格雷姆打个招呼
Okay, I'm gonna go say hello to Graham,
省得在这儿受他折磨
spare myself the torture.
让他干点活儿
Get him to do some work for a change.
他应该给我修吉普的
He's supposed to be fixing my Jeep.
我很爱你女儿
I love your daughter very much
因为她和你一样  不轻易相信别人
because, among other things, she's skeptical, like you.
你不介意我问一句吧
Then you won't mind me asking you
你打算怎么赚钱养她
how you intend to support her.
她不肯接受我的任何帮助
She won't accept any help from me,
至少在我活着的时候
at least not while I'm alive.
她靠写作赚的那点钱
And the money she makes from writing
可不够两个人花
is gonna be spread pretty thin for two.
不用担心
Don't worry,
我自有打算
I'm considering several options.
石油怎么样
What about oil?
石油都是在挖掘过去
Oil's all about digging in the past.
这我从来不感兴趣
I've never been that interested.
给世界提供动力还不足以吸引你吗
Powering the world isn't interesting enough for you?
未来石油供大于求
With a glut on the horizon,
创新改革必定缓慢
innovation's bound to be slow.
如果我是你
If I were you,
就会扩展业务范围
I would be looking to diversify.
做什么
Into what?
有前瞻性  有潜力改变世界的东西
Something forward-looking with the potential to change everything.
我依然认为  那是技术
For me, that's still tech
除非最后证明我错了
and will be until proven otherwise.
我是这样想的  乔
Here's what I think, Joe.
就凭你复杂多变的工作经历
I think with your checkered work history --
这已经是好听的说法了
and that's the nice way of putting all the things I've heard --
你现在并没有太多选择
you don't have a whole lot of options right now,
无论是在技术或者别的领域
in tech or anywhere else.
你拿不到好推荐
With your abysmal references,
你想去应聘华夫饼铛推销员都困难
I think you'd have a tough time getting a job selling waffle irons.
你真想让自己经受那些吗
You'd really want to put yourself through all that?
无论付出什么代价
Whatever it takes.
我只是在陈述冰冷的事实
I'm just stating cold facts.
你找工作不会轻松
You won't easily get a new job.
如果我说得不够清楚  我在向你提供工作
If I haven't made myself clear, I'm offering you one.
我不知道你认为我是什么人
I don't know who you think I am,
但我不是在寻求施舍
but I'm not looking for charity.
我也没有在施舍
And I'm not looking to give it.
今天  今天是梦想实验室日
Today -- today is dream lab day.
我要把它建立起来
I'm gonna really set 'er up, you know.
不废话  切实行动
No more talking, just action.
我甚至可能自学C语言
You know, I may even teach myself C.
谁说我只会做硬件了
Who says i'm only hardware?
在闲暇时间  我真的想学学做饭
Oh, in my spare time, i really want to learn to cook.
真正好好做饭
Like, you know, really cook,
为我们所有人
you know, for all for us.
今晚有什么特殊要求吗  亲爱的老婆
Any special requests tonight, dear wife?
香橙鸭
Duck à l'orange?
好啊  什么
Yeah, what?
你找到脆脆的...
Did you find the crunchy --
你还好吗
Hey, you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
还好吧
I mean, sort of.
我昨天去银行
I went to the bank yesterday
想提高穆特尼的信用额度
to try and increase Mutiny's credit limit.
柜员就只是嘲笑我
The guy there just laughed at me.
你需要多少
How much you need?
哈哈  你付不起的
Ha-ha, you couldn't afford it.
所以才需要风投啊
Well, that's what schmancy VCs are for.
如果我们能搞定他的话
Yeah, well, if we can close him.
没有长期数据
I'm afraid without longer term data --
他对我们的预计增幅恐怕不会信服
he'll balk at our projected growth.
你在德州仪器时业务陈述一向做得很棒
Look, you always killed your presentations at TI.
这也不会有什么不同
This is gonna be no different.
你只需要走进去
You just go in there,
自信地讲一个好故事
you tell a good story with confidence.
爸爸
Daddy!
叫这么急  还以为是房子着火了呢
Oh, you know, you'd think the house was on fire.
飞来啦  宝贝
Flying in, babe!
必须是重入式  递归的
It has to be re-entrant, recursive.
除了排序  选择或迭代
I mean, you never need to branch except to sequence,
不需要分支
select, or iterate.
-我不...  -我在改进图形界面
- I don't... - I'm trying to help the graphics.
什么  即使让网络崩溃吗
What, even if it makes the network crash?
按功能模块再做一次测试  今晚之前做好
Do another rev in blocks, and do it by tonight.
卡梅伦  可用了
Cameron, it's up.
什么
What?
为什么这段代码没弄好
Why is this sequence not done?
卡梅伦  我们上线了
Cameron, we're live.
什么
What?
独立的即时消息  没有游戏
Stand-alone messaging, no game.
我们管它叫穆特尼社区
We're calling it Mutiny Community,
但也可以改成更时髦的名字
but we're open to something snappier.
你做这个花了多少时间
How many hours did this take you?
没多少
Not too many.
唐娜  我们聊过了
Donna, we talked about this.
你可以尝试这个
You can try this,
但是游戏的开发都跟不上了
but we're falling behind on games.
等等  等等  闭嘴  闭嘴
Wait, wait, shut up, shut up.
看  我们第一个用户
Look, our first user.
这是什么游戏的
"没有游戏  只是聊天
"No game, just chat.
你好"
"Hi, how are you?"
屠梦者79退出了房间
好吧  你能去把游戏代码写完吗
Okay, can you please go finish your game code now,
做咱们公司真正该做的事
like what we actually do at this company?
老天
Oh, God.
我没指望盛情欢迎
I didn't expect a ticker tape,
但至少给我把椅子啊
but I could use a chair.
老天
Oh, God.
天啊
Whoo, Jesus.
第一次监狱暴乱  两个脚踝都粉碎性骨折
The first prison riot, I broke both my ankles. I shattered them.
他们用防暴水枪冲我
They got me with the water cannon.
把我从两层的窄道上冲下来
They blasted me off a second-story catwalk.
摔在水泥地上
Right on the concrete.
你们有谁真信了吗
God dang, are you guys buying any of that?
天呐  你们是有什么毛病啊
Jesus, what's wrong with you?
你好吗  博斯沃思
How you doing, Bosworth?
阿基  来拜见传说
Arki, meet a legend.
嗯嗯  好吧
Yeah, sure, sure.
你什么时候出来的  博斯
When'd you get out, Boz?
我前两天挖隧道跑出来了
Well, I tunneled out a couple days ago, by God,
但我得找个地方先洗洗尘
but, uh, just had to find me a shower.
我准备好了
I'm ready to go.
来吧  开始派对吧
Come on, let's get the party started.
我坐哪里
Where do I sit?
等等  你要在这儿工作了
Wait, you're working here now?
-太棒了  -是的  刚成为17号员工
- Awesome! - Yes, sir. Just signed on as employee number 17.
-好棒  -你在监狱里学会打字没
- Dude. - Did you learn how to type while you were in prison?
你个小混蛋
You son of a bitch.
这里可以吗  我就坐那儿了
It's good here? I'll sit there, for God's sake.
之前流过鼻血吗
You have nosebleeds before?
小时候被恶霸欺负时流过  后来就没有了
No, not since Garrett Faloona used to punch me on the playground.
有其他症状吗  头痛  恶心
You have any other symptoms-- headache, nausea,
关节痛  任何症状
soreness of the joints, anything?
没有  没什么
No, no, not really.
我是说...
I mean, I, um...
我们搭建电脑赶工期时
back when we were chasing deadlines on this computer we were building,
我有段时间用过可卡因来提神
mm, I used cocaine for a brief spurt.
好吧
Okay.
多短期  用了多少
How brief and how much?
两三个月吧
Two, three months.
量不太清楚
And, I don't know,
需要时就用了
whenever we needed it.
我们时间真的很紧  所以...
We were under the gun, so...
可卡因是莨菪烷生物碱  会灼伤鼻粘膜
Cocaine is a tropane alkaloid that can burn your nasal membranes
如果你没有先发心脏病或中风而死的话
if you don't die from a heart attack or a stroke first.
我三个月前就戒掉了  我...
N-n-no, I stopped cold three months ago. I'm--
那很好  我可不希望你女儿失去父亲
Good. I'd hate to see your daughters grow up fatherless.
那太可悲了
That would be sad.
不用担心...
Well...
我不是那种容易上瘾的人
no, I'm not one of those people that gets addicted to stuff easily.
我能保证
I can promise you that.
你至少该跟我说一声
You could've at least told me.
怎么了  我们都受够了当老大
What? We're both sick of playing boss.
等他了解了情况
I mean, as soon as he gets up to speed,
就能帮我们解决很多事
he can take stuff off our plates.
-他管理了卡迪夫22年呢  -我知道
- He ran Cardiff for 22 years. - I know.
穆特尼不是卡迪夫
Mutiny is not Cardiff.
这公司的意义就在于此
That's the whole point.
-我知道  -卡梅伦  他是前科犯
- I know. - Cameron, he's an ex-convict,
绝不是最佳雇佣选择
which is not exactly the smartest hire
我们正想多拉点投资呢
when we're in the market for more funding.
我们现在资金如此不足
And when we're this strapped for cash,
你要把钱浪费在
you're gonna waste it on somebody
一个一点都不懂网络技术的人身上吗
that doesn't know a bitmap from a baud rate?
别这么做
Don't do this.
别因为愧疚或同情他
Don't threaten what we're building here
而威胁到我们辛苦建立的东西
out of guilt or feeling sorry for him.
唐娜  他留定了
Donna, he stays.
我们说好一起管理
We talked about being in this together.
也谈过沟通的重要性
We talked about communication being key.
这和之前讲的完全不一样
This... this isn't what we talked about.
怎么了
What?
我在想
I was just thinking about...
你爸要我去工作
your father offering me that job.
是啊
Yeah.
我还在生他的气呢
I mean, I'm still mad at him.
典型的雅各布·维勒式伏击
It's the classic Jacob Wheeler ambush.
假如我接受呢
What if I took it?
为什么啊
Well, why would you?
我们以前还打趣
I mean, we joked about that.
你管那地方叫坟场
You called that place a mausoleum,
"以化石为基础的买卖"
"A business literally built on fossils."
我知道  但是
I know, but, I don't know...
我查了很多资料
I've been doing a bunch of reading.
三维计算机建模正在撼动整个产业
3-D computer modeling is really shaking up the industry,
改变了钻井的方式和选地
changing where and how to drill.
我愿意参与进去
I could get into that,
帮着西方集团走向未来
help take Westgroup into the future.
那其他工作呢
What about those other jobs?
都没要我
Didn't pan out.
我知道也不该就因此去你爸的石油公司干活儿
I know, that's no reason to go work for your father's oil company,
但大致了解之后  莎拉
but I've kicked the tires on this, Sara,
我真的挺感兴趣
and I'm genuinely interested.
也可能只是不想再苦等了
Or maybe you're just tired of waiting.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我很清楚过去一年赋闲在家
Look, I know that this past year being on the sidelines
你很不好受
has been really tough for you.
但你之前说在等别人来联系你
But when you said you were waiting for contact,
我没料到是想要我爸来找你
I didn't think you meant from my father.
如果你实在觉得怪
If this is too weird for you,
我可以再等别的
then I can wait around for something else to...
不会  不用
No, no.
我不想看你不开心
I don't want you to be unhappy.
那我们得搬到达拉斯去
And we'd have to move to Dallas.
这会让你不开心吗
Would that make you unhappy?
乔
Joe...
如果你想要这份工作
if you want the job,
这份工作  接受吧
this job, take it.
没问题  接受吧
Of course, take it.
C编程语言
欢迎来到
穆特尼
正在连接
-站住  -...事实上每月的消耗率...
- Stop! - "...revenue, our monthly burn rate is actually..."
小心
Watch out!
-抱歉  唐娜  -小伙子们
- Oh, Donna, I'm sorry. - Guys.
我瞄的是那个小杂种
I was aiming for that mongrel.
伙计们  到外面去玩
Guys, just take it outside.
别想跑  哪去了
Cube not okay. Where is it?
唐娜  你老公的电话
Donna, it's your husband.
戈登
Hi, Gordon.
听到没有
You hear that?
猜我在干吗
Guess what I'm doing.
用调制解调器
Um, using a modem?
没错  但怎么用的呢
Aha, but how?
会不会是我又买了一根电话线
Could it be that I got a second phone line
这样我们可以同时上网和打电话
so that we could go online and talk at the same time?
没错
Yeah, that's...
可能是这样
that's probably it.
跟风投的会面进展如何
How'd your VC meeting go?
安排在一小时后
Uh, it's in an hour, which is...
听着  戈登  我得挂了
Look, Gordon, I've gotta go.
要我帮你听听吗
Yeah, well, you wanna run your pitch by me?
或许我可以...帮点忙
Or maybe I could, uh, you know, help out and...
不好意思
Really, I'm sorry.
爱你  宝贝
I love you, darling.
回家见吧
I'll see you at home, okay?
玩家名  胡子帅哥
好啊
All right.
你想来一局吗  小子
You wanna play, little man, huh?
什么  不
What? No!
你不可能先射击
There's no way you shot first.
我在游戏开始后100毫秒就开火了
I shot 100 milliseconds after the game started.
-你好  -斯坦  我是戈登
- Hello? - Stan, it's Gordo.
你现在在干什么呢
What are you doing right now?
太好了  我没迟到
Oh, good, I'm not late.
悠悠球被电压保护器绊倒了
Yo-Yo tripped over a surge protector,
让三台XT飞上了天
sent three XTs flying.
万幸的是  他们落在了一堆披萨盒上
Luckily, a stack of pizza boxes broke their fall.
被混乱所救
Saved by squalor.
-怎么了  -你换成这衣服了
- What? - You changed into that?
-没错  -我应该穿成那样吗
- Yeah, I-- - Was I supposed to dress like that?
那我该穿得休闲点吗
Well, was I supposed to dress down?
天哪  也许你是对的
Oh, God, maybe you're right.
也许他们就想要年轻叛逆型的
Maybe they want young and rebellious.
也或许你牛仔裤上有洞
Yeah, or maybe they don't invest a million bucks in you
他们就不会投一百万给你
if you've got holes in your jeans.
该死  我本可以...
Damn it, I could've--
打扰  豪伊小姐和克拉克女士
Excuse me, Miss Howe, Miss Clark?
邦汉姆先生现在可以见你们了
Mr. Bondham will see you now.
你们发行了国际象棋  西洋跳棋  双陆棋
Okay, so you have put up chess, checkers, backgammon,
坦克大战和视差
"Tank Battle," and "Parallax."
而且前三个不算  那几个根本没意思
And ignoring the first three because who cares about those,
15个月出了两款游戏
that's two games in 15 months.
你们貌似并不着急啊
Not exactly in a hurry, are we?
其实  视差有21关
Well, "Parallax" actually has 21 chapters,
每关的设定都不一样
each one with a totally different world.
-所以它不...  -嗯  我侄子原先很着迷
- So it's not-- - Yeah, my nephew got hooked on it.
-这就是我同意见面的原因  -很好
- That's why I took this meeting. - Cool.
但他在大概13关的时候就没兴趣了
But then he got bored around chapter, uh, 13
-那个大冰乌贼  -是螃蟹
- when the giant ice squids... - Crabs.
吃了爱斯基摩宫殿什么的
ate the Eskimo palace or whatever.
他说和别人联机打游戏很好玩
He said it's fun to play with other people,
但游戏本身就不行了
but the game itself-- you know, pfft.
和雅达利正在出的新品没法比
It's nowhere near as good as what Atari's been popping out.
我觉得如果你侄子对编程有更多了解
I think if your nephew understood coding a little better,
他会觉得视差还是很厉害的
he'd think "Parallax" was pretty cool.
卡带游戏也许现在看上去不错
Um, look, cartridge games may look better for a while,
但网游才是未来趋势
but online gaming is the future.
如果能持续盈利的话
Only if there's a profitable way to sustain it.
没错  这就是我们来这里的原因
That's exactly right. And that's why we're here.
我们的网络过载了
Our network is overloaded,
限制了我们新用户的订阅
limiting our ability to sign up new subscribers.
你怎么知道他们存在呢
How do you even know they're out there?
只有10%的美国人有电脑
Only 10% of Americans have computers.
其中只有15%的人有调制解调器
Only 15% of them have modems.
更别说你们还只用康懋达电脑
Not to mention the fact that you're only on Commodores.
你们怎能知道
I mean, how do you really know
存在足够多的用户
that there are enough users out there
能让我们赚的盆满钵满吗
to make us all a killing?
我们就是知道  靠店内咨询  口耳相传
We just do. I mean, in-store inquiries, word of mouth.
有很多数据可以证明
There's a whole world of data.
是嘛  有那种证据  我当然无话可说
Oh, yeah, with proof like that, how can I argue with you?
邦汉姆先生
Look, Mr. Bondham,
如果我们能筹到钱购买十台"彗星"小型计算机
if we had the capital to buy 10 11/750s--
-3.5万一台  二手机  -是3.2万
- 35 grand a pop, used. - 32-- 32,
外加维持本财年
plus additional funding to cover operations
运营的资金
through the end of the fiscal year,
-那我觉得  -那孩子呢
- then I think... - What about kids?
什么
Excuse me?
你们想要或者有小孩吗
Do you have or want kids?
-我没有  -我有两个
- No. - I have two.
这有什么关系呢
What does that have to do with it?
我要给一家公司注资
Well, when I invest in a company,
我不仅是在赌一个点子  还有人
I don't just bet on an idea, I bet on the people.
成功并不容易
Success is no Sunday drive.
也不是冰箱上贴着的待办事项
It's not another to-do tacked to the fridge.
如果你俩真像你们说的那样  要经营公司
If you two, as you claim, are really gonna run this business,
我需要知道你们会长期全身心投入进去
I need to know that you're fully committed, long-term.
甚至超过对孩子的投入
Even over, you know, biological imperatives.
抱歉  你到底给不给我们钱
Sorry, are you gonna give us the money or not?
乔·麦克米伦
Joe MacMillan?
是我  你好
Yeah, uh, hello.
尤金·鲍迪奇  欢迎来到数据录入部
Hey, Eugene Bowdich. Welcome to Data Entry.
我带你去你的办公桌
I'll show you to your desk.
我去了23楼做入职
I was on 23 for orientation
人力资源叫我来地下二层
and HR told me to come down to B2
我想这肯定是搞错了吧
and I think there's been a mistake.
没错啊  你的名字在我的板子上呢
Oh, no mistake. You're on my clipboard.
西方集团能源  你应该知道
Now, Westgroup Energy, if you're not aware,
是个拥有九家全资子公司的母公司
is really a parent corporation to nine wholly owned subsidiaries,
他们所有的数据录入都由我们负责
and we do DE for all of them.
颜色编码篮  充足标签
Color-coded baskets, redundantly labeled,
对应不同数据源
correspond to different inputs.
数字化公司记录的程序
The process of digitizing the company's records
从1974年就开始了
was begun in 1974,
不过当然  自那之后我们已经有了很大进步
though clearly since then we've made great strides.
雅各布知道这就是派给我的工作吗
Does Jacob know this is what I'm working on?
你是说雅各布·维勒吗
You mean Jacob Wheeler?
算了
Uh, never mind.
好  还有问题吗
All right, any questions?
那么  就是
So, it's-- it's just-- it's, uh...
人工操作吗
d-done by hand?
当然不是  我们使用的是光学字符辨识
Oh, no, we use optical character recognition,
只是需要人工校对
which-- which we correct by hand.
对于个别难以辨认的图像
For particularly naughty images,
你还可以用那个大家伙呢
you might even get to use the Big Kahuna over there.
但得先向我申请  好吗
But you'll have to ask me first, okay?
好吗
Okay?
-好的  -好
- Okay. - All right.
下班时请记得打卡
Please clock out at the end of your shift,
另外请保持卫生间整洁
and we labor to keep the bathrooms tidy.
相信这点你一定能做到
I trust you'll comply.
去死去死  你这头笨猪
Die, die, die, you disgusting pig dog!
吃我一炮
Eat it! Eat it!
天呐  戈登  你要把键盘按坏了
Jeez, Gordon, you're gonna break the keyboard.
看到吗  那里
You see? Right there.
应该是你死  不是我死
You should be dead, not me.
游戏像是有计时问题
It's like the timing's off or something.
来  再来一次
Here, come on, let's go again.
抽屉还有
There's more in the drawer.
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
我只是惊讶你居然还
I'm surprised you're still--
那不是只是帮我们完成
I mean, I thought it was just a goof
巨人专业版的消遣吗
when we were finishing the Giant Pro.
没错  斯坦  真是
It was, Stan, jeez.
我就是找到些剩下的
Look, I found some left over.
那你要我怎么办  直接扔了吗
What am I supposed to do, throw it away?
快点  继续玩
You know? Come on, let's just play.
等等  这次
Okay, wait-- hey, this time,
数到三  然后开火
okay, on three, fire your tank.
准备好了吗
Ready?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
该死  到底怎么回事啊
Damn it! What is going on here?
不对劲  你我都看到了是我先开火的
I mean, we-- something's going-- we both saw that I fired first.
这游戏绝对是
I mean, there's gotta be some sort of
有问题还是什么的
glitch or something in the--
我们先休息一下吧  喝瓶啤酒
Why don't we take a break? Maybe grab a beer?
不行  我得打给唐娜告诉她这事
No, I gotta call Donna and tell her about this.
这可是她们的旗舰游戏之一呀
I mean, this is one of their flagship games.
我笨了  电话线都占着呢
Duh, we're using both lines.
好吧  我直接过去一趟吧
Uh, well, I guess I'll just go over there.
-你开车行吗  -我当然可以开
- You okay to drive? - Yeah, of course I'm okay to drive.
该死  斯坦  你能帮我个忙吗
Oh, shit! Stan, will you help me out?
去学校帮我接下孩子行吗
Will you go pick up the girls from school?
-什么  不行  -为什么不行
- What? No. - What do you mean no?
我都快两年没见过她们了
I mean, I haven't seen 'em in, like, two years.
给你  看看
Well, here, look.
你能认出来的
You can figure it out.
给你  可以给她们买点零食什么的
Here, and feel free to buy 'em some snacks or something.
他捡肥皂了  他捡肥皂了
He touched the soap. He touched the soap.
真好笑  姑娘们  真好笑
Very clever, ladies. Very clever.
哥们  干得漂亮  看见他的表情了吗
Man, that was awesome. Did you see the look on his face?
-笑死我了  -太有趣了
- Yeah, perfect. - Priceless.
那可是火灾隐患
That's a fire hazard.
-唐娜在哪  -看看谁来了
- Hey, where's Donna? - Whoa, look who's here.
你不应该带着刚拿到的钱
Shouldn't you be in Tahiti or something
去塔希提那种地方吗
with all the money you just made?
坦克大战
Look, there's a major problem
有大问题  游戏不公平
with "Tank Battle." The game's not fair.
兄弟  我们现在有更头疼的事
Dude, we've got bigger headaches right now.
幸好卡梅伦不在
And it's a good thing Cameron isn't here.
是啊  我真走运
Oh, yeah, lucky me.
听着  有时我向对手开炮
Listen, there's times when I fire at my opponent
但游戏没有识别于是我就被打死了
and the game doesn't read it and I get killed.
会不会是因为你开炮晚了
Oh, wow, well, couldn't it be that you're just shooting second?
不是的  斯坦和我多次同时开炮
No, Stan and I fired at the same time over and over
即便是我先开炮  结果也是随机的
and even when I cheated, the results were random.
你们的系统从多个调制解调器读取输入  对吧
Your system's reading inputs from multiple modems, right?
-是啊  -那么在一局游戏中
- Duh. - So in a given game cycle,
令牌逐个检查  看谁的坦克开了火
the token checks them one at a time to see who fired their tank.
-这我们知道  -对吧
- We know this, man. - Okay?
如果你想说
And if you're saying
令牌检查到时
whoever's fire command
恰好已发出开火命令的人
happens to be  next in line when the token sweeps it
便被识别为击杀成功
is awarded the kill,
那你就说对了
then you're right.
恭喜你  但所有玩家都冒着同样的风险
Congratulations. But every user shares that hazard equally.
但结果并不显示谁先开炮  结果是随机的
But it doesn't reflect who shot first. I mean, it's random.
如果结果是随机的那玩游戏还有什么意义
What's the point of playing a game if the outcome is random?
没关系的  好吗
Look, it doesn't matter, okay?
我有办法
I got a fix for ya.
你不是搞硬件的吗
Aren't you just the hardware guy?
我还拥有伯克利大学计算机科学的学位
Well, I'm also degree-in-computer-science-from-Berkeley guy,
那也是唐娜的学校
where Donna went,
我的分数高得能让你们的老二蔫下去
with honors and top grades that'd make your penis shrivel,
所以如果你们能闭会儿嘴还能学到点东西
so maybe if you shut up for a second, you could learn something.
给每个调制解调器的输入信息加上时间戳
You time-stamp the input from each individual modem
令牌检查完一圈后也加上时间戳
and at the end of each complete token pass.
判定击杀前将它们按正确的时间顺序排列
You put them in the correct time sequence before you execute them.
这样一来  先开炮的人...
That way, whoever shot first... -
就赢了
...wins.
-厉害  -太聪明了
- That's solid. - That is not dumb.
我们应该  我们应该这么办
We should, uh-- we should do that.
兄弟们  找到唐娜
Um, g-guys, find Donna.
有人要绑架她的孩子
Someone tried to kidnap her kids.
该死  斯坦
Damn it, Stan.
让我接电话
Give me the phone.
我是戈登·克拉克
It's, uh, Gordon Clark here.
我知道了
Yeah, I see.
其实那是我朋友  我让他...
Actually, that was a friend of mine that I asked to--
是啊  我们应该先打个电话的
yeah, we're supposed to call first.
对不起给你们添麻烦了  霍金斯校长
Well, I'm-- I'm sorry for the trouble, Principal Hawkins.
不  不  不  我马上过去
Oh, no, no, no. I'll be right there.
连送一周披萨  只要不说出去
Pizza deliveries for a week if not a single word.
一个月  再加汽水
A month, plus soda.
我可以挨我妻子的臭骂  我只是不想而已
I can take heat from my wife, I'd just prefer not to.
-两个月  -一个月  行吗
- Two months. - Look, one month, okay?
成交  臭小子们
Deal, you little rats.
他们想要的不是未来或愿景
I mean, they don't want what's next or vision,
他们要男人
they want an Adam's apple.
至少我们的穿着无所谓
Well, at least what we wore didn't matter.
是啊  他们在搞恶作剧
There's been some prankin' going on, sure.
-卡梅伦  -什么事
- Cameron? - What?
来看看这个
You should see this.
大概一个小时前电力出问题了
They had a power fraz about an hour ago,
烧掉了一个连接器什么的
fried a connector or some such.
你还是去看看吧
You might want to go take a look at that.
-嗯  好  -嗯
- Yeah. Yeah. - Yeah.
跟我们的视差一模一样  但图像更好
It's exactly like our "Parallax," Except with better graphics.
我也发现了  你从哪找到这个的
I can see that. Where did you get this?
朋友的朋友从他朋友那儿拷贝的  免费
A friend of a friend copied it from his friend, free.
有个混蛋剽窃了视差  而且在免费传播
Some asshole ripped off "Parallax" And is just giving it away.
-他黑了我们的网络吗  -我不  让开
- He hacked into our network? - I don't-- look, here.
这是谁干的  我们知道吗
Who did this? Do we know?
某个家伙  没人认识他
Some dude. No one knows him,
但据说他在最后一个子程序代码的注释里签了名
but supposedly he signed it in the comments to his final subroutine.
汤姆·兰顿
Tom Rendon.
好  查查名单  看他是不是用户
Okay, check the list. See if he's a subscriber.
汤·兰顿  该死的
Rendon, T. Holy shit.
克莱兰顿路2123号  他居然在线
2123 Clarendon Street. He's even still logging on.
你是汤姆·兰顿吗
Hey, Tom Rendon?
-你们是谁  -你偷了我们的游戏
- Who are you? - Hey, we're the people whose game you stole.
穆特尼的人
Oh, Mutiny.
太酷了  我正希望
Very cool. I was kind of hoping
你们能发现呢  你们觉得怎么样
it would find its way to you guys. What'd you think?
-兰顿先生  -叫我汤姆
- Mr. Rendon-- - Tom.
兰顿先生  我们很感谢你过去
Mr. Rendon, we appreciate your business
十个月的支持  但你不能偷我们的游戏
for the last 10 months, but you can't just copy our game
还指望不被发现
and expect to get away with it.
我没有直接剽窃视差
Well, I didn't just copy "Parallax,"
而是改进了很多
I made it a whole lot better,
如果我想不被抓的话
and if I wanted to get away with it,
就不会署名了
I might've, you know, not s-- not signed it.
我要说的是你必须停止这种行为
My point is you have to stop
否则我们就不得不采取法律措施了
or we'll be forced to take legal action.
好吧  好吧
Oh, okay. All right.
我在市中心的查坦-沃特金斯律所IT部工作
Well, I run IT at Chatham & Watkins downtown,
所以我能帮你们找个好律师
so I can help you find a good lawyer.
你觉得我们在开玩笑吗
Oh, you think this is a joke?
你觉得两个姑娘不能告倒你吗
What, you think a couple of girls won't sue your ass into the ground?
不是
No.
你们不会告我  因为那样我就会生气
You won't sue me because then you're gonna make me mad
就不会告诉你们怎么改进游戏
and then I'm not gonna tell you how to make your game better.
-你们想进来喝两杯吗  -好了
- You guys wanna come in? We could have a couple beers. - Okay.
我可以把一切都说给你们听
I can lay everything out for you.
听着  你或许觉得你改进了游戏
Listen, you might think you made the game better,
但我们做的是线上游戏
but we do games online.
六种颜色和液体监测仪一样的图像效果
Yes, six colors, that fluid scan,
在康懋达上也许能行
it might work on a Commodore,
-但如果要用电话线传输...  -我懂
- but if you want to do it across phone-- - I get it! I get it.
我懂  你们不想用结构凌乱的代码
I get it. You don't want to use spaghetti code,
你们想要事倍功半
you want to make more with less.
这才是真正的艺术
That's the real art of it.
你们试过画面交换或抖色处理吗
Have you ever tried page flipping, dithering?
-没  我是编程新手  -配合反锯齿
- No, I'm new to coding. - Combined with anti-aliasing?
别全用C语言做  能节省内存
Don't do it all on C. You'll also cut back on memory.
如果你们想听指导  还是可以来喝两杯的
Beer offer still stands if you want that tutorial.
好吧  别再那么做了  好吗
Okay, look, just don't do it again, okay?
不然我们问题就大了
Or we're gonna have a serious problem.
遵命  女士  我错了
Yes, ma'ams. Mea culpa.
我特此取消订阅
I hereby cancel my subscription.
我都不想再吃这个了
Mm, I don't even want this anymore.
伙计们  挖到金矿了
Dudes, mother lode.
这是博斯寄给卡梅伦的
It's to Cameron from Boz.
我猜这一定是他在监狱里寄的最后一封信
Bet it's the last one he sent from jail.
-你要把它怎么办  -你觉得呢
- What are you gonna do with it? - What do you think?
博斯出去抽烟了
Boz went out for smokes.
等等  那样不会把信毁了吗
Wait, won't that ruin it?
我能修复
I can fix it.
13年来我都是这么看我姐妹的信的
Did it to my sisters for 13 years.
快点  快点
Come on, come on.
快点
Come on.
太棒了
Nice.
"亲爱的卡梅伦
"Dear Cameron..."
我简单写两句
...I'll keep this short
因为我知道  我希望不久后就能见到你
'cause I know or hope I'll see you soon.
约翰逊的情况还是那样
More of the same with Johnson.
我不说那些烦心事给你添堵了
I won't burden you again with that whole mess.
我只是在努力忘却这一切"
I'm just trying to put it behind me."
这时候很适合讲菊花笑话
Cue appropriate butt sex joke.
"我一直在想我妻子  卡梅伦
"I think about my wife, Cameron.
前妻  我还想到我儿子
Ex-wife, I mean. And I think about my sons,
不知等我出狱他们是否还会认得我
if they'll know me when I get out
是否还愿认我
and, God, if they'll want to.
这是最让我痛苦的
That's what hurts the most.
这是最戳我心的利刃"
That's the real knife to my heart."
-还是别闹了  -怎么了  多有意思
- Hey, uh, maybe we should stop. - Why? It's too good.
是啊  别闹了
Yeah, man, let's just forget it.
继续念
Go on.
念完了
Finish it.
继续
Go on.
"我做的事值得吗
"Was what I did worth it?
老实说  我觉得值得
Honestly, I think so.
我在上帝的眼中还是好人吗
Am I good in the eyes of God?
或许这很糟  但我并不在乎
Maybe this is terrible, but I don't really care.
说到底  是我的内心  而不是他更重要
It's me inside that matters, not Him, push come to shove.
抱歉跟你说这些话
Sorry to lay all this on you,
但我也只能跟你说说了
but you're all I got to talk to,
这黑洞之中的一抹亮光
the light in this dark hole.
博斯"
Boz."
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我们就是在胡闹
We were just goofing off.
滚出去  回家
Get out of here. Go home.
我住这里
This is where I live.
那就滚远点  让我有一阵看不见你
Then go someplace I can't see you for a long time, okay?
我们合作真的很好
You know, we really work well together.
或许我们该再启动一个项目
Maybe we should start another project.
或许我可以出资
Maybe I could even fund it.
至少直到成型
At least till it gets off the ground.
-真的吗  -是啊  为什么不呢
- You'd do that? - Yeah, why not?
那就太好了
Man, that'd be sweet.
但我要去北加州了
But I'm headed up to good old NorCal.
加州吗
But-- California?
你已经拿到工作了吗
Do you have a job lined up?
没有  只是去碰运气
Nope, just rolling the dice.
被卡迪夫解雇那天我就订了机票
Booked my ticket the day I got my pink slip at Cardiff.
外面有很多厉害的人物啊  斯坦
A lot of big dogs out there, Stanny.
弱肉强食什么的
You know, eat or be eaten.
那挺好  正好我饿了
Yeah, well, good, 'cause I'm hungry.
其他人  小心了
Ruff, ruff, you other mutts.
你不需要搭档的  戈登
Ah, you don't need a partner, Gordo.
不管你设计出什么  肯定都很棒
I'm sure whatever you dream up will be incredible.
我们再玩一局吧
L-let's play another round.
他们现在应该已经重编码了
I'm sure they've got it recoded by now.
好了  数到三  这次别作弊了
All right, on three. No cheating this time.
各就位  预备
All right, line 'em up. Ready?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
为什么延时了
Why the lag?
好奇怪
That's weird.
低用户数量
Low user volume,
而且都用的专线
each on a dedicated line?
延迟应该几乎难以察觉
I mean, the delay should be imperceptible.
绝不会这么严重
Nothing near this bad.
这东西我可不会出钱买
I wouldn't pay for this crap.
那些白痴肯定给搞砸了
The idiots must've messed it up.
这下游戏更差了
Now the game sucks even more.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
怎么回事  新时间戳代码
I don't understand. The new time-stamp code
应该至多只会增加100多毫秒
should only take an extra 100 milliseconds, tops.
现在线上有多少用户
How many users we got online?
132个
132.
再看一遍  二逼
Uh, yeah, check again, dumbass.
我这边看是80个在线调制解调器
I'm showing 80 live modems.
等等  慢着
Wait a second, hold it.
这里有不是我们写的代码
There's code in here that we didn't write.
什么  怎么回事
What? What's going on?
有人黑入了坦克大战
Someone hacked into "Tank Battle."
写了让多个用户用一根电话线玩游戏的代码
They added bytes that let multiple users play on a single phone line.
这太厉害了
This is awesome.
就像一个孩子买了张电影票
Like a kid when he buys a movie ticket
然后又传给其他朋友
and then passes it back to his friends.
出现了多少这样的情况
How many hacks are there like this?
这里有根线上有12个用户
Here's one that's allowing 12 users on a single line.
12  等等  什么  这怎么回事
12-- wait, what? How did this happen?
你们的代码里有后门吗
Do you guys have back doors in your code?
-嗯  我们总...  -你们跟别人说了吗
- Yeah, we always use some-- - Did you tell anyone about them?
当然没有了
No, no, of course not.
好了  我们删除代码
Okay, look, look, just-- we'll delete the bytes.
不许一线多人  然后再考虑如何防护
No free rides. And then we'll talk about security.
等等
Wait, wait, hold on.
如果是用户在黑我们  我应该能追踪到
If the hacks are from a user, I think I can trace them.
你怎么做到的
How'd you do it?
-什么  -别装  告诉我
- What? - No, just tell me, okay?
你从我兜里偷了钱
You stole money out of my pocket
你让12个调制解调器共用一根电话线
by getting 12 modems to share a single phone line.
你理应告诉我你怎么做到的
You owe me how you did it.
我建了个专用交换机软件
I built a PBX in software,
我自己的用户交换机
my own private branch exchange.
12个根本不算什么
And 12 is nothing.
我在努力达到3倍的量
I'm working on three times that.
如果穆特尼变成那样
If Mutiny could do that,
单个用户的收费就会减这么多倍
it would make our overhead per user that many times smaller.
你心算的吗
You do that in your head?
你想知道我怎么想的吗
You want to know what I think?
别说太长
If it doesn't take too long
我不想把鸡烤糊了
'cause I really don't want to burn my chicken.
你很厉害  你可以随便黑任何人
You're good at this. I mean, you could be hacking into anyone.
但你没有
But are you?
计算机服务  通用电气信息交换网络
CompuServe? GEnie?
你没动他们
I don't think so.
我认为你只在
I mean, I think you're only
克隆我们的游戏  黑我们的网络
cloning our games and hacking our network.
所以你要么是成天恨我们
So either you spend all your time hating us
要么就是真心欣赏我们的工作
or you really love what we do.
-谁说这事那么耗时了  -我说
- Who says it takes that much time? - I do.
我查了上月
I checked our top-10 users
在线时长最长的10名用户
last month based on hours spent online.
你是第四
You were number four.
我可以为你建个专用交换机软件
I could set up a software PBX for you.
50个都没问题
Hell, I could set up 50.
你是在让我给你份工作吗
Are you asking for a job?
不  我喜欢我的工作
No, no. I like my job.
真的  拿钱不少  又不累
I do. It pays well, the hours are good.
我闲暇时间可以研究游戏
I work on games in my spare time.
好了  你剽窃了视差
Okay, just because you ripped off "Parallax"
不代表你就是游戏设计师了
does not make you a game designer.
还需要概念设计
There's still the actual concept,
原创发明
the original invention.
不是往别人创造的东西上
You know, not just sprinkling fairy dust
撒仙尘
on what somebody else has created.
既然我不想应聘工作  能别教训我吗
Since I don't want the job, can I not have the lecture as well?
如果你需要那个专用交换机打给我
Okay? Give me a call if you want that PBX.
好吧
Okay.
我今天找了三个律师
I talked to three different lawyers today.
他们说最不能做的
They said the worst thing we could do
就是自己去找兰顿
is go confront Rendon ourselves,
希望你没干什么蠢事
so I hope you didn't do anything stupid.
他入侵我们是为了吸引我们的注意
He's hacking us to get our attention.
我觉得他真的很厉害
And I think he's the real deal.
真不敢相信我会说这话
I can't believe I'm saying this,
但我觉得我们该雇佣他
but I think we should hire him.
他也有意  他给了我他的简历
He's interested. He gave me his resume,
但我想先跟你商量
but I wanted to talk to you first, so...
你已经雇了他  是吗
You already hired him, didn't you?
太好了  我整个下午都在计划法律策略
Great. I spent the entire afternoon planning our legal strategy.
真是不浪费资源啊
What an efficient use of resources.
你给他开了多少钱
What did you offer him?
2.5万
$25,000.
改成两万  他会接受的
Make it 20. He'll take it.
我打给了他工作的律所
I called the law office where he works.
我一说出他做了什么  他们就忙不迭地骂他
Once I told them what he was up to, they threw him under the bus.
他上两次绩效评估很差
His last two performance reviews have been awful.
他们本就打算开除他  他也知道
They were gonna fire him anyway and he knows it.
你如果想多给他钱  就把我的工资给他吧
And if you want to pay him more, you can give him my salary.
因为如果你总这么单方面做决定
Because if you keep making unilateral decisions like this,
我就不会留下了
I will not be sticking around, okay?
嗯  好
Yeah, okay.
谢谢
And thank you.
-喂  -你今天过得怎么样
- Hello? - Hey, how was your day?
不不不  你先说
Oh, no, no, no. You first.
今天在办公室过得如何啊  亲爱的
How was your day at the office, honey?
挺好的  我们在计算机化记录
Good, we're computerizing records,
把一切录入档案
getting everything archived.
还有呢
And?
有时候
And, well, sometimes
我还能使用微缩胶片机
I get to use the microfiche machine.
不可小瞧哦
Not to be sneezed at.
还需要人批准才行呢
You, uh, need approval.
好吧  这是我的错
All right, this is my fault.
得了  当然不是
Oh, come on. Of course it isn't.
他在为彼得惩罚你
Yeah, he's punishing you for Peter.
什么意思
What do you mean?
彼得  他骗了我父亲
Peter-- he hooked my father,
让他加入几桩交易
got him deep on a few deals.
一个在苏黎世  还有别的
One in Zurich and this other thing.
但全都是虚的  交易都是假的
But nothing ever materialized. The deals weren't real.
最后  我父亲损失了几百万
All told, my father lost a few million.
这都是我们离婚前不久发生的
And this all happened right before we got divorced.
我父亲因为我而没有提防
My father let his guard down because of me,
彼得也没还他钱
and Peter never paid him back a penny.
你怎么没跟我说过
How come you never told me that?
因为
Because I--
我为此责怪自己
I hate myself for it, you know?
我不希望你视我为受害者
I-- I didn't want you to see me as a victim
或是白痴
or an idiot.
但我这就给我父亲打电话
But, you know, I'm gonna-- I'm calling my father right now.
他无权这么对你
He has no right to do this to you.
不  莎拉  慢着
No, Sara, wait.
我一整天都为此闷闷不乐
I've been stewing about this all day.
我心想这肯定是有原因的
I thought there had to be some reason.
现在清楚了  你父亲在试探我
Well, now it's clear-- your dad is testing me.
他想看看我的斤两
He wants to take my measure.
就凭你刚刚跟我说的  如果你是我女儿
And after what you just told me, if you were my daughter,
我也会这么做
I would do the same thing.
但这太扯淡了  根本浪费时间
Yeah, but it's stupid. It's a waste.
我不会让你...
You know, I'm not gonna let you just--
我不会的  别担心
I won't, don't worry.
我是大人了  我也在吸取教训
I'm a big boy. I'm learning a lot.
我们让这事先缓缓
So we can just let this breathe a sec.
好吗
Yeah?
好
Okay.
还有件事
Uh, one more thing.
就凭我的工资
With what I'm getting paid,
别想在北公园租双卧公寓了
a two-bedroom in North Park's not gonna happen.
我不在乎
I don't care. I mean...
我们可以支帐篷啊
we could pitch a tent.
回家见
I'll see you at home.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
Yeah, me, too.
要叫她们吗
Should I call 'em?
我很期待让你们尝尝这个
I'm really excited for you guys to taste this.
我在垃圾箱里看到外卖盒子了  戈登
I saw the takeout containers in the trash, Gordon.
就考你眼力呢
Just testing.
你喜欢索尔餐厅的焖菜  是吧
You like Sal's cacciatore, right?
至少你对坦克大战的痴迷有所成效
Hey, at least your obsession with "Tank Battle" paid off.
我的程序猿们说你去过
My coder monkeys said you came by,
还说你的时间戳补丁很天才
that your time-stamp fix was genius.
是啊
Oh, yeah, yeah.
我就是工作时休息了一下
I took a little break from work, so...
当然了  胡子帅哥
Oh, sure, you did, sexy beard.
我们的记录显示你在线9小时呢
Our log says you were online for nine hours.
我肯定是忘关了
Hmm, well, I must've left it on.
而且  那些笨蛋
Anyways, the way those nitwits
编的码让情况更糟了
coded it made the problem even worse.
他们给你看延迟问题了吗
Did they show you the delay?
嗯  但那是因为汤姆
Yeah, but that was because of Tom,
是个用户  黑了我们的系统
this user who hacked our system
他还剽窃了视差  结果卡梅伦还是雇了他
who Cameron wound up hiring after he ripped off "Parallax."
嗯  有道理
Sure, makes sense.
很高兴她还是个疯子
Good to know she's still insane.
据说  他有突破发现
Well, apparently, he had this breakthrough.
他搭建了一个专用交换机软件
It's a software PBX
最多可允许50名用户
that allows up to 50 users
用一根电话线玩
to play on a single phone line.
-那太厉害了  -是啊
- That would be huge. - Yeah.
我有点想回去找那个风投的混蛋
I'm tempted to go back to that VC jerk
看看他是否愿意改主意  但我做不到
and see if it'll change his mind, but I can't bring myself.
穆特尼有多少潜在用户
How many potential users are out there for Mutiny?
你这话跟他一样  戈登  这无从知道啊
Now you sound like him. Gordon, there's no way to know.
但这不是关键吗  这会影响
But isn't that critical? I mean, it'll affect your valuation
你下轮融资的评估
for the next round of financing.
是啊  但又不能预测未来
Yeah, but there's no crystal ball.
是啊  但是  唐娜  或许能呢
Yeah, no, but, Donna, maybe there is.
你需要现有用户网络的分布图
Look, you need a map of the existing network.
穆特尼随时能看到子设备
Mutiny only sees a subset at any given time,
但是
but what if--
如果所有可以登录的人  不管怎么登录
what if anyone who could log on, legitimately or not,
同时登录呢
did it at the same time?
那得有多少人啊
How many people would that be?
-戈登  -我这就得去研究了
- Gordon! - Look, I gotta get started on this.
自己吃吧
Eat without me!
你可以在这里工作  但不能住这里
You know, you can work here, but you cannot live here.
嗯
Yeah.
你的信对我很重要
Your letters meant a lot to me.
你寄的最后一封
The last one you sent,
你签的是凯瑟琳
you signed it Catherine.
卡梅伦是我爸的名字
Cameron was my dad's name.
他死后我就开始用他的名字
I started using it after he died.
我以前会往越南给他写信
And I used to write letters to him in Vietnam,
我肯定是手误了
so I must've written that by mistake.
听我说  博斯
Listen, Boz...
你不能随便把信放在这里
you can't just keep stuffing envelopes around here.
我们的账目一团乱
I mean, our books are a mess.
回收账款什么的
Accounts retrievable, that whole thing--
得了  你知道那叫"应收账款"
Oh, come on, you know it's "Receivable."
不不  我不知道
No, no, I don't know that.
这事我做不好
Look, I suck at this.
我们需要你看看  发挥总裁的魔力
We need you to take a look at it, work some CEO magic.
而且我们还需要人帮忙筹钱
Plus we need help raising money.
我们会给你安排办公室  给你个拐角...
I mean, we'll get you an office, we'll get you your own corner--
凯瑟琳
Catherine.
我就是需要点时间考虑清楚
I just need some time to work some stuff out.
理清思路
Get my head straight.
-博斯  -得了  你虽然聪明
- Boz. - Oh, come on, as smart as you are,
但我还是比你更了解自己
I think I know myself a little bit better than you do.
你能让我来这里工作真是好心
My God, it's beautiful, you lettin' me work here.
但是
But I--
我还没准备好呢
I'm just ready for it, not yet.
你需要多久
How long do you need?
老实说  我不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
维勒先生  这是刚送来给您的
Mr. Wheeler, this just came for you.
有留言吗
Was there a note?
是的  夹在里面的
Yes, sir. It was stuck inside.
-给我读读  卡罗琳  -好的
- Read it, Caroline, will you? - Of course.
就写了"多谢给我机会"
It just says, "Thank you for the opportunity."
没有签名  好像是华夫饼铛
It's not signed. I think it's a waffle iron.
我知道是谁送的
I know who it's from.